Guide to the James Taylor Tanner papers, 1935-1990.
Tanner, James Taylor papers, 1935-1990.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
James Taylor Tanner papers, 1935-1990.
2665
James T. (James Taylor) Tanner.
.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, articles, manuscripts, field notes, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers relating to James T. Tanner's career as an ornithologist.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Ornithologist.
Cornell University Class of 1935.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence and typed articles relating to ornithology in general and the Ivory-billed Woodpecker in particular; field notes on the Cornell University-American Museum of Natural History Expedition, 1935; notes on the Ivory-billed Woodpecker, 1936-1968; "The Ivory-billed Woodpecker: Research Report #1 of the National Audubon Society," by James T. Tanner, 1942, annotated by Dr. Tanner, 1989; and field notes on the Imperial Woodpecker Expedition, 1962. Also locality records, indexed by species; notes and a manuscript describing the birds of Cape May, NJ, with an emphasis on the portection of hawks, 1936; notes and a manuscript about observations made in Cortland County, NY, in 1933, as an undergraduate project for Arthur Allen; notes about melanism in birds, including an original drawing, 1934 and 1948-49; field notes on Junco study in the Great Smoky Mountains; notes on canoe trips; field notes for a willet study at Long Beach, NC, 1976; bird records from Long Beach, NC, 1961-1990; and data on the birds of Tennessee. Also, birding records from Ithaca and Cortland areas (1933-36); Glacier National Park (1934); Cape May, NJ (1936); Elk Lake, NY (1936 and 1945); Johnson City, TN (1940-42); Chesapeake Bay (1943); St. Simons Island, GA (1943); Boston (1945); Knoxville, TN (1947-1965); and Chiricahua, AZ (1956).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Tanner, James T.; Allen, Arthur A. (Arthur Augustus), 1885-1964.
Subjects:
Ornithology.; Ornithology--Field work.; Birds--Research.; Woodpeckers.; Ivory-billed woodpecker.; Imperial woodpecker.; Scientific expeditions.; Bird watching--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Bird watching--New York (State)--Cortland.; Bird watching--Montana.; Bird watching--New Jersey--Cape May.; Bird watching--New York (State)--Elk Lake.; Bird watching--Tennessee--Johnson City.; Bird watching--Georgia--St. Simons Island.; Bird watching--Massachusetts--Boston.; Bird watching--Tennessee--Knoxville.; Bird watching--Arizona--Chiricahua.; Ornithologists.
Places:
Chesapeake Bay (Md. and Va.); Glacier National Park (Mont.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Field notes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence re: Ivory-bill material, 1938-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ivory-bill reports, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Field notes Cornell-American Museum of Natural History Expedition, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "The Ivory-Billed Woodpecker," Research Report No. 1 of the National Audubon Society, 127 pp., published Oct. 1942, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Notebook of field notes, includes South Carolina and Texas, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Manuscript map of Singer Tract, Madison Parish, LA (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence re: Ivory-billed Woodpecker, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence re: Ivory-billed Woodpecker, 1942-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence of James T. Tanner on Cuban Ivory-billed woodpecker, 1957, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Congaree Swamp - James T. Tanner, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- James Taylor Tanner, 1914-1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence of James T. Tanner on the Imperial Woodpecker, 1941-1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Birds of Tennessee, 1925-1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bird observation log by family, life list, 1932-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bird observation log by family, 1931-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bird observation log by family, 1932-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Notes on Juncos in the Smokies, 1951-1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Beach Book, Willet study, field notes at Long Beach, N.C., 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Long Beach, 1975-1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Beach Book, 1961-1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Bird Records from Boston - 1945, Chesapeake Bay - 1943, St. Simoni, Id. - 1943, Elk Lake - 1945, 1943, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Birds Cortland County [N.Y.], 1933, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Cape May Reports, 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Color Patterns, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Old Bird Records: Ithaca, Cortland, N.Y. areas; Glacier National Park; Cape May; Elk Lake and Paradox Lake, N.Y., 1933-1936 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Bird records, East Tennessee Area, Johnson City, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Bird records, Knoxville and vicinity, Tennessee, Jan. 1, 1947-Oct. 8, 1949, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Bird records, Knoxville, Tenn. and vicinity, Nov. 1, 1949-, 1949-1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Chiricahua Mountains, Arizona, June-July, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Notes on canoe trips, 1965-1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Other Correspondence including Ivory-billed, 1945-1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- A Postscript on Ivory-Bills, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- A Forest Alive, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- The Suwannee River, 1890 and 1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- The Population Implosion (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Symposium Summary: A Long-Term View of Old Growth Deciduous Forests (Box 2, Folder 22)
- A Long-Term View of Old Growth Deciduous Forests James T. Tanner and Paul B. Hamel, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Changing Ranges of Birds in Tennesse, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Analysis of Phenological Events: The Start of Egg-layings by Birds (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Suggestions for Research on the Cuban Ivory-Billed Woodpecker (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Waterfowl on the ORNL Reservation, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Comments on Land Use Planning, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Notes for Talks, 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Reprints (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Guide to the Study of Animal Populations: Publishing Agreement and Book Reviews, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Clippings, Maps, Consultant Report, etc. (Box 2, Folder 32)
- University of Tennessee Graduate Program in Ecology (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Letters, Papers, Articles about Tanner (Box 2, Folder 34)
- The Ivory-Billed Woodpecker; Dover edition, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Report on the Search for the Ivory-Billed Woodpecker in Eastern Texas, January 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Book reviews by James Tanner, 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Negatives and Photos with Chris (hawk); Photos, 1931-1932; 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence RE: Ivory-billed woodpecker, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- John V. Dennis Recording, presumptive Ivory-billed woodpecker near Neches River, East Texas, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Eastman Lantern Slides - Singer Tract, Louisiana - Ivory-billed Woodpecker and related subjects, March 1938 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Eastman Lantern Slides - Singer Tract, Louisiana; Mississippi River at Natchez; Natural Bridge, Virginia, August 1938 (Box 3, Folder 7)